Alex "Daniel" Prieu

Software Developer

(615) 397-4198

Email: GitHub: Personal site:

Daprieu@gmail.com https://github.com/daprieu https://alex-prieu.netlify.app/

ABOUT ME

Growing up I spent my days hiking trails and exploring parks. Biology always came naturally for me and my love for learning about nature never ended. After college I worked as both a Park Ranger and as a Zookeeper. In both positions I often found myself being more technologically interested than my colleagues and was usually the one to fix old electronics and troubleshoot new equipment. I welcomed the idea of sensors and programs that could automate the work for us and we could monitor those systems adjusting parameters to make them work as efficiently as possible. This interest followed me everywhere, I taught myself about most of what I know about computers in my free time and love making tech projects at home too. When I started grabbing code from GitHub and learning that I could write code too, I knew then that I wanted to make a career switch. My goal as a Software Developer is to design applications for the future and to increase the efficiency in our lives both time and energy, while mitigating the loss of our natural resources.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript

React.js

HTML

CSS

Bootstrap

React-Bootstrap

Python

Django

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School - Technical Education

January 2021 - Current

NSS is a six-month intensive, full-time software development bootcamp focusing on HTML, CSS, Javascript, React and server-side fundamentals with Python and Django.

- Single-page application development with React and with a focus on modern ES6+ Javascript
- features and modular code
- Project management with issue tickets and GitHub Projects
- Database planning by building entity relationship diagrams (ERD) to define relationships with an
- emphasis on maintaining a flat data structure
- Utilized vanilla JavaScript (ES6), and React.js to create single page dynamic web applications using
- full CRUD functionality
- Styled applications using CSS, Bootstrap, reactstrap, and Material UI
- Completed 6 group project sprints while fully remote, comfortable with Slack, Zoom, GitHub
- Projects, and wireframes for group communication and collaboration

Projects:

- Backyard-Botanist (Front-end Capstone): https://github.com/daprieu/Backyard-Botanist
- Personal Website: https://github.com/daprieu/Personal-Website
- Holiday Road (Group Project): https://github.com/daprieu/Personal-Website

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nashville Zoo at Grassmere - Life Support System Technician

June 2018 - December 2020

- Aquatic pump and filter technician, dealing with the teardowns and rebuilding of pumps, plumbing
 exhibits, and maintaining a variety of chemical and mechanical filtration for all exhibits around the
 zoo.
- Provide animal husbandry to our American Alligator and Koi fish where I maintain their exhibits and provide enrichment training to these animals as well as giving public talks to inform guests about our animals.

U.S. Army Corps of Engineers - Park Ranger

June 2017 - May 2018

- Conducted water safety programs, local radio PSA's, interpretive outreach, boat patrol, and dock inspections
- Lead a monthly safety meeting, recorded traffic counters, performed general maintenance, and assisted senior rangers with everyday tasks

Express Oil Change, and Service Center - Automotive Technician/ Floor Lead

August 2012 - May 2016

- Followed and enforced a standard order of procedure to ensure the proper safety and accuracy of each vehicle inspection before and after servicing
- Assisted a mechanic in normal operations in removing and replacing vital vehicle parts, such as brake parts, alternators, starters and more

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Communication

- Acknowledging others when conversing and asking questions to better understand their problems and information
- Being able to use acquired knowledge and know-how to explain techniques and practices

Problem solving

- Coordinated work solutions in collaboration within my own department as well as other departments to ensure that a job or task can be done efficiently and in a timely manner
- Developed new methods and ideas for mechanical and spatial issues and disseminated information to those that are directly involved

Technical

- Worked with pool and pond chemicals, and ensure the safe handling and tracking of the chemicals for safety of guests and animals
- Ensure proper handling and use of specific plumbing/ pump, parts, fittings, tools, and PPE. Proficient
 in computer database management for keeping logs of water quality and chemistry and formulating
 notes for current exhibits

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School - Full-Stack Software Developer June 2021

Front-end development, language (Javascript), stack and patterns as well as a server-side language (python), stack and patterns.

Tennessee Technological University - Wildlife and Fisheries Science December 2017

Bachelor of Science Degree in Wildlife and Fisheries Science, Conservation Biology Concentration.